<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="utgs.xsl" type="text/xsl" version="1.0"?>

<document>
    <title>Useless Temporary Game Solutions</title>
    <sub-title>The Real Boost for making Multimedia &amp; Games.</sub-title>

    <chapters>
        <toc>
            <link>
                <title><i>Useless</i> - Multimedia &amp; Games Library (Overview)</title>
                <href>UselessOverview.xml</href>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title><i>KooLiXP</i> - Compiled Instructions (Overview)</title>
                <href>KooLiXPOverview.xml#Overview</href>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title><i>KooLiXP</i> - Compiled Instructions (Reference Manual)</title>
                <href>KooLiXPCompiler.xml</href>
            </link>
        </toc>
        <chapter>
            <title>Preface</title>
            <name>Preface</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    Hi. I am Radoslaw Kolasinski, M.Sc. of Computer Science.
                    I've been Lead Programer involved in sevral commercial game projects, for 5 years.
                    The work presented here is derived from these projects.
                    The components of this library were used commercialy in a wide variety of game types,
                    such as: tycoon management, 3rd person advanture, or pack of mini-games for kids.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <b>On 11-th May 2005</b>, I got the <b>clerical permission</b>, signed by my boss, to place these components into <b>public domain</b>.
                    After then, I was looking for free <i>Subversion</i> host server.
                    If you have access to this project, it means I have found one <code lang="text">;-)</code>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Project Components:
                    <ul>
                        <li><n>Useless</n><d>utility &amp; multimedia library.</d></li>
                        <li><n>KooLib</n><d>utility &amp; KooLiXP library.</d></li>
                        <li><n>Dynamo</n><d>dynamic module loading w/ KooLiXP bound.</d></li>
                        <li><n>strmbase</n><d>public Microsoft Direct Show base classes.</d></li>
                        <li><n>KooLiXP</n><d>executable program linked against all libraries.</d></li>
                        <li><n>vc7.0</n><d>Microsoft Visual C++ 7.0 projects.</d></li>
                        <li><n>vc7.1</n><d>Microsoft Visual C++ 7.1 projects.</d></li>
                        <li><n>gcc</n><d>gcc build &amp; clean scripts.</d></li>
                        <li><n>examples</n><d>examples of usage.</d></li>
                        <li><n>www</n><d>This documentation.</d></li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Virtues:
                    <ll>
                        <li> BSD License,</li>
                        <li> X-platform project via multiple layers of abstraction,</li>
                        <li> Scripting language, easy to learn, with many bindings to components of the library,</li>
                        <li> Extensible thru external modules loaded at run-time,</li>
                        <li> Tested against comercial game projects,</li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Features:
                    <ll>
                        <li> Encryption Capable Virtual Filesystem,</li>
                        <li> GUI User Interface Library,</li>
                        <li> XML Resource Library,</li>
                        <li> C++ Utility Templates such as functors, signals, associative containers,</li>
                        <li> DirectShow streaming thru OpenGL textures synchronized with GUI rendering,</li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>What is <i>KooLiXP</i> ? - An introduction to scripts.</title>
            <name>AbountKooLiXP</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    KooLiXP is LISP like functional, and Python like objective language.
                    XML was choosen as its form, so it may look similar to XSLT language.
                    The language is realy easy to learn and use.
                </p>
                <p>
                    What's cooking in <i>KooLiXP</i>:
                    <ll>
                        <li>built-in, just-in-time compiler, which provides ability to create compiled functions from selected parts of code,</li>
                        <li>function curring, which provides ability to in-place creation of function objects with bound selected function and given parameters,</li>
                        <li>infinite streams, when you create listnode providing a function as a <q>tail</q>,</li>
                        <li>built-in operations such as: <i>map</i>, <i>fold</i>, <i>zip</i>, <i>range</i>, <i>seek</i>, <i>head</i> providing
                            easy and fast iteration algorithms,</li>
                        <li>runtime in-place objects, which means you are able to create object with members without having defined any class,</li>
                        <li>runtime object templates, actually there are no classes, so you need to create just constructor function,</li>
                        <li>import built-in library bindings,</li>
                        <li>dynamic library linking (win32 DLL or linux SO). </li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <link>
                        <title>See KooLiXP Overview...</title>
                        <href>KooLiXPOverview.xml</href>
                    </link>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <link>
                        <title>See KooLiXP complex example ...</title>
                        <href>KooLiXPComplexExample.xml</href>
                    </link>
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>What is <i>Useless</i> ? - An introduction to C++ modules.</title>
            <name>AboutUseless</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    Useless is Multimedia &amp; Games library.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Layers in <i>Useless</i> module:
                    <ll>
                        <li>static layer of system interfaces, which provides system windows and events translation to window-level signals,</li>
                        <li>abstract layer of system interfaces, which provides hardware acceleration for graphics, sound and other multimedia,</li>
                        <li>abstract layer of images, which provides mechanisms to load pixmaps from files onto hardware surfaces,</li>
                        <li>abstract layer of sounds, which provides mechanisms to load samples from files into hardware buffers,</li>
                        <li>layer of graphical user interface (GUI), which provides widgets, skins and fonts,</li>
                        <li>layer of xml resources, which provides creation of items from other layers, based on scipts.</li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <link>
                        <title>See Useless overview...</title>
                        <href>UselessOverview.xml</href>
                    </link>
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Thanx</title>
            <name>Thanx</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    I'd like to send big thanx to my boss, who gave me a legal right to place all this stuff into a public domain.
                </p>
                <p>
                    I'd also like to thank my good colegue from company, with whom I've discussed several library topics.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Big thanx for all those people who have beta-tested this software in many projects.
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Finale</title>
            <name>Finale</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    Use this library for whatever you want.
                </p>
                <p>
                    I would be pleased if you don't forget to tell me about it.
                    Just send me some e-mail note at <mailto>koolas@gmail.com</mailto>.
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
    </chapters>

</document>
